Berlin, Germany +55 (32) 999168204 andrerpena@gmail.com http://andrerpena.me

André Pena

Software engineer with 12 years of experience in web development and architecture.

I'm currently a Senior Frontend Engineer Zalando (e-commerce, Germany). My previous experience includes 5 years as a Software Architect at Thomson Reuters, where I played a central role releasing LegalOne, the core platform for most of Thomson Reuters legal products in Latin America and Iberia.

I currently work with TypeScript, JavaScript, React and Node.js, Docker and Kubernetes. I have certifications in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C# and ASP.NET.

Know more about me here: http://andrerpena.me/

Technical Skills

Likes: typescript javascript reactjs node.js docker kubernetes

Experience

Senior Software Developer – Zalando SE

Feb 2018 → Current

node.js, javascript, typescript, reactjs, amazon-web-services, docker, kubernetes

Zalando is a massive scale e-commerce business in Germany. I'm currently helping rebuilding the front-end platform using React and TypeScript.

Full Stack Sofware Engineer – Bluestone Group reactjs, typescript, javascript, ecmascript-6, c#, asp.net-mvc, .net

Jun 2017 → Current

I worked in Fintech business, building an online tool for collecting and processing loan requests from brokers world-wide. Even though I was a full-stack engineer, I'm worked mostly in the client side using React / Redux / TypeScript. The server stack was ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework and SQL Server.

Technical software architect / Lead web developer – Thomson Reuters

Sep 2012 → Jun 2017

c#, html, entity-framework, javascript, css, asp.net, .net, sql-server, node.js, reactjs, redux, python

Responsibilities:

- Architect a framework for implementing large-scale data-centric business applications.
- · Help creating POCs and implementing such framework.
- Provide guidance for developers when it comes to best practices, scalability, extensibility and maintainabilty.
- Drive innovation and propose modern and efficient solutions according to evolving industry standards.

Challenges of the projects we create:

- Create a platform for making it easy to create SCRUD heavy applications.
- Make the applications localizable, both in terms of translation, number/date formats and multi-currency support, as well as providing a way for the regions to customize the views and behavior.

Examples of problems we tackle:

- How to implement localization, including time zones, currency, number and date formats and translations?
- How to make the application modular? That is, how to deliver only some particular modules depending on the customer demands?
- How to deploy an application in a country that have variations in the data fields, business rules and texts. How to implement the differences without forking the original application?
- How to make the applications extensible to the end user? A key point to go global with a line of business App is
 to give the most flexibility to the end user. He/she must have the ability to customize texts, change the application
 data fields and manipulate the layout.

Tech lead / Senior Web Developer – Novaprolink Technologia .net, c#, asp.net-mvc, entity-framework, mstest

Jun 2009 → Aug 2012

We migrated our line-of-business web framework to ASP.NET MVC using Entity Framework as the ORM solution. I was the tech lead in the process, helping creating the framework to support the developers and making them productive.

I was responsible for:

- · General application layout (HTML, CSS and JavaScript)
- · jQuery plug-ins development
- ASP.NET MVC helpers, specially to make it easy to create data-driven forms, and integrating with the jQuery plugins.
- · Entity Framework architecture.
- · Access Control.
- Licensing.
- · Reporting.
- MSTest architecture.

Web Developer - Novaprolink Tecnologia

Jun 2007 → May 2009

.net, c#, webforms, winforms, designer, visual-studio-addins, orm

We started developing a framework for creating line-of-business / model-driven apps for ASP.NET WebForms. I was involved in every aspect of the design, from the ground up:

- · Visual Studio Add-ins development.
- Data Access Layer with DevExpress eXpress Persistent Objects.
- Web-Control development, involving both client and server side, emphasizing rich data-aware capabilities.
- Web-Control designers development (Windows Forms applications aimed to enhance the developer experience while designing controls)
- Application flow: Authentication, Authorization, Access Control, Licencing, Testing...

This project has been deprecated in favor of a newer one. I'm no longer active with ASP.NET Webforms and Visual Studio Addins development

Intern – JGP Jun 2006 \rightarrow Jun 2007 adobe-flex, java, action-script, cairngorm

I was a intern working with Adobe Flex and Java for a stock market consulting company. I worked with both the front-end and back-end. This period allowed me to get very familiar with object orientation and web-services.

Education

Bachelors in Information Science (Currently studying remotely) – Universidade Estácio de Sá

2015 → Current

Certifications

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 html5, css3, javascript

Nov 2016 → Current

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in C# c#, .net

Sep 2016 → Current

Microsoft Certified Professional

Apr 2012 → Current

c#, asp.net, .net

c#, asp.net, asp.net-mvc, .net

Jan 2011 → Current

Projects & Interests

Stack Overflow - https://stackoverflow.com/users/192729/andr%c3%a9-pena

Oct 2009 → Current

Written 339 answers. Active in javascript, reactjs, .net, asp.net-mvc-4, c# and 11 other tags.

Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: .NET Framework 4, Web Applications

react-mde – https://github.com/andrerpena/react-mde node, ecmascript-6, reactjs, gulp

Dec 2016 → Current

React Markdown Editor inspired by GitHub

redux-autoform-bootstrap-ui – https://github.com/andrerpena/redux-autoform-bootstrap-ui javascript

Jul 2016 → Current

Bootstrap UI extension for redux-autoform

	redux-autoform – https://github.com/andrerpena/redux-autoform javascript	Jul 2016 → Current
	Create Redux-Forms dynamically out of metadata	
	L1PM – https://github.com/andrerpena/legalone-pacote-melhorias vue.js, sass, node.js, gulp, google-chrome-extension	Jul 2016 → Current
	A Chrome Extension to add user experience and new features to Legal One, the project I work for on my day job.	
	<pre>quotr – https://github.com/andrerpena/quotr javascript</pre>	Oct 2015 → Current
	A Node.js CLI for displaying stock exchange quotes	
	react-metaform – https://github.com/gearz-lab/react-metaform javascript	Aug 2015 → Current
	A library for dynamically generating React forms out of metadata	
	chatjs – https://github.com/andrerpena/chatjs typescript	Sep 2014 → Current
	Platform-independent jQuery plugin for chatting	
	SmartRecords – https://github.com/andrerpena/SmartRecords c#	Aug 2013 → Current
	A simple .NET report generation library	
	Cerebello – https://github.com/andrerpena/Cerebello c#	Apr 2012 → Current
	Medical practice administration system	
Apps & Software	AboutDevs – https://aboutdevs.com/ typescript, reactjs, redux, node.js, express, postgresql	Jan 2018
	A website builder for developers with an integrated search engine for IT recruiters	
Others	Background – Background	
	I'm a full-stack web developer with experience in C#/ASP.NET and Node.js, as well as HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery/React	
	e-mail: andrerpena at gmail.com	
Readings	C# in Depth, 3rd Edition – Jon Skeet – http://www.amazon.com/Depth-3rd-Edition-Jon-Skeet/dp/161729134X	
	Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja – John Resig, Bear Bibeault – http://www.amazon.com/Secrets-JavaScript-Ninja-John-Resig/dp/193398869X	
Tools	First Computer: 486 DX2 Favorite Editor: WebStorm	